
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
    >

<channel>
    <title>SGCC BLOG</title>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sgucblog.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>http://www.sgucblog.com</link>
    <description>A Shepherding Tool of San Gabriel Community Church</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 05:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.1</generator>
    <item>
        <title>Feed Your Heart. Feed It! (Scottish Accent)</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/14/feed-your-heart-feed-it-scottish-accent/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/14/feed-your-heart-feed-it-scottish-accent/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 22:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Smith]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=1026</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[This blog post title is informed by the Scotts Lawn Care commercials with the Scottish guy named Scott, I believe. I thought of it when I recently read an article entitled A Bible Reading Plan for Readers. The article&#8217;s main theme is that we should go after scripture and devour it in big clumps.  It has always [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog post title is informed by the Scotts Lawn Care commercials with the Scottish guy named Scott, I believe. I thought of it when I recently read an article entitled <a href="&lt;a href=">A Bible Reading Plan for Readers</a>. The article&#8217;s main theme is that we should go after scripture and devour it in big clumps.  It has always seemed strange to me that we would read scripture so differently than how it was communicated originally. The Bible is a collection of books, and these books are to be read, at least every once in a while, as whole pieces, and not simply excerpted as single-page devotionals.</p>
<p>I was reminded of this article (and ones like it) on the Gospel Coalition website by a friend some days ago. It&#8217;s an interesting perspective and a short but worthwhile read.</p>
<p>&#8211;Geoff</p>
<p><a href="http://thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/tgc/2013/12/27/a-bible-reading-plan-for-readers/">Click here to view article.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/14/feed-your-heart-feed-it-scottish-accent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bible-Saturated People</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/07/bible-saturated-people/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/07/bible-saturated-people/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 22:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Dave]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=1016</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[In the summer of 1990 I was in Manila, Philippines. The plan was to be in Manila for five weeks as part of a campaign with Campus Crusade for Christ to saturate the city with the Gospel of Jesus. Many of the different ministries of CCC, including ours, the high school ministry, had planned various [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/sponge.jpeg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1017" src="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/sponge.jpeg" alt="sponge" width="203" height="248" /></a> In the summer of 1990 I was in Manila, Philippines. The plan was to be in Manila for five weeks as part of a campaign with Campus Crusade for Christ to saturate the city with the Gospel of Jesus. Many of the different ministries of CCC, including ours, the high school ministry, had planned various outreaches throughout the city. The high school ministry was to speak in every public high school in Manila. Everything was pre-arranged. Scout teams had spent months preparing. Money had been raised. Extensive evangelism training had taken place.</p>
<p>I arrived in Manila early, while most were still in the U.S. or en route. Then, the unexpected happened: the CCC leadership received an anonymous death threat. (I can’t recall if the group claimed to be Marxist or Muslim. Both are possible in the Philippines.) So, quickly our plans changed. About a third of our group stayed in Manila, while the rest were diverted to Hong Kong, Macau, Hawaii (ya, bummer right?) and Singapore. My group went to Singapore. The summer of 1990 ended up being very different than planned. Yet, at the end of the summer, as we reflected upon the work that had been accomplished, we realized that all the goals had still been reached. In addition, unexpected evangelism and discipleship had occurred in the other locations. How did that happen? Our convictions were set before the crisis hit. We trusted in the guidance of God’s Holy Spirit, the power of His Word, and our staff and students were trained and equipped for ministry. So, when the crisis hit, we just moved locations, and the ministry continued.</p>
<p>Crises rarely come when we expect them. We cannot put them on our calendar. Thus, we need to be prepared. Growing up in southern California in the seventies, I remember practicing “duck and cover” drills in school. When the bell rang, we would all duck under our desks and cover our heads, rehearsing what we would do if “the big one” hit or the Soviets bombed us.</p>
<p>All of us will go through times of crisis: death, cancer, job loss, prodigal children, marital strife, etc. God is the only one strong enough, wise enough, faithful enough to bring us through the storms of life. The better we know him, his attributes, his promises, his absolute sovereignty over every detail of life and his intimate care for his children, the better prepared we are for the days of darkness that may lie ahead. We come to know God in his holy, inspired word, the Bible, and as we obey him. So, when is the best time to prepare: before the crisis, or after it hits? Clearly, the best time to prepare is before the crisis.</p>
<p>This past weekend, about fifty or so of us from the church and school attended <em>Impact</em>, a conference put on by the ministry <em>Children Desiring God</em>. Our children’s ministry and school chapel program have been using <em>CDG’s </em>curriculum for several years now.</p>
<p>During one of the main sessions, the speaker, David Michael, was talking about the importance of being Bible-saturated people. As he spoke, next to him on the stage was a bucket of water in the shape of a large black Bible. At one point, he reached into the bucket and pulled out a sponge, the big yellow kind you see used for washing cars. The sponge was filled with water. As he lifted the heavy sponge, water poured out from the bottom. He squeezed the sponge and more water oozed out. He dipped the sponge back in the water, then, drawing it out, poked at it with a long stick. Again water ran out. As he repeatedly drew the sponge in and out of the water he said, “Bible-saturated people drip Bible. Everything we observe, are taught, consider, decide, and conclude is shaped and influenced by the Word of God. If we are saturated by the Word, we have an ever-present and infinitely wise Counselor, Comforter, and Interpreter to guide us and others through us.”</p>
<p>So, how are you doing at becoming a Bible-saturated person? Jesus at the close of his Sermon on the Mount said this:<em> “Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat on that house, but it did not fall, because it had been founded on the rock. And everyone who hears these words of mine and does not do them will be like a foolish man who built his house on the sand. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and beat against that house, and it fell, and great was the fall of it.”(Matthew 7:24-27)</em></p>
<p>&#8211;Pastor Dave</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/07/bible-saturated-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Have You Visited Our Library Lately?</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/02/have-you-visited-our-library-lately/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/02/have-you-visited-our-library-lately/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Greg]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=986</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[Our church library has a wonderful collection of books. The collection contains many volumes that address specific topics like family, relationships, determining God&#8217;s will for your life, finances, and many other areas. You will find an outstanding assortment of authors, including Charles Spurgeon, C.S. Lewis, J.I. Packer and John Piper. As you would expect, there [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/photo1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-987 size-thumbnail" src="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/photo1-150x150.jpg" alt="photo[1]" width="150" height="150" /></a> Our church library has a wonderful collection of books. The collection contains many volumes that address specific topics like family, relationships, determining God&#8217;s will for your life, finances, and many other areas. You will find an outstanding assortment of authors, including Charles Spurgeon, C.S. Lewis, J.I. Packer and John Piper. As you would expect, there are commentaries on every book of the Bible, reference books like concordances, Bible encyclopedias and atlases, and a solid selection of translations and Study Bibles. We also have books covering a wide variety of subject areas including Missions, Apologetics, Church History, and Theology.</p>
<p>For those interested in delving deeper into a passage, there are resources in Hebrew and Greek, many of which are very usable by those of us who have never studied these Biblical languages. We also are planning to add a Children&#8217;s Bookshelf that will prove to be a great resource for our families. When we moved our worship services back to the Sanctuary building, our church library moved with us. It is located inside the Sanctuary on the north side of the building, between the cry room and restrooms.</p>
<p>If you have never used the library before, you will find it very simple to borrow books. Simply note the books you&#8217;d like in the notebook displayed on the table. You may keep a book for as long as you need, but please keep in mind that others in the church family may also wish to use it. When you are finished, simply return the book(s) to the red box you will find on the bottom shelf of the center bookcase, and then note the date next to your original entry in the notebook. That&#8217;s it! We add titles regularly. If there is a particular book you would like to see added to the collection, please let me know and we will see if we can include it. A good cross-section of our church family is already using this helpful resource. If you haven&#8217;t had a chance yet, I would encourage you to take a look at the church library this Sunday.</p>
<p>–Pastor Greg</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/05/02/have-you-visited-our-library-lately/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Heavens Declare The Glory Of God!</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/23/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/23/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 23:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Greg]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=975</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[David exclaimed this truth 3000 years ago as he penned the opening of Psalm 19. He undoubtedly spent many nights alone as a young shepherd gazing at the stars and contemplating the greatness of the God who spoke into existence all that filled his eyes. For many of us these kinds of experiences are difficult [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>David exclaimed this truth 3000 years ago as he penned the opening of Psalm 19. He undoubtedly spent many nights alone as a young shepherd gazing at the stars and contemplating the greatness of the God who spoke into existence all that filled his eyes.</p>
<p>For many of us these kinds of experiences are difficult to come by today. Demanding schedules seem to crowd out the time for such solitude and reflection, and the lights of our cities would veil the stars should we finally make the time to gaze at them anyway. But despite these significant disadvantages, we have the opportunity to be struck by the majesty of God’s heavens in ways that David himself could never imagine.</p>
<p>For years now I have followed a NASA website dubbed “APOD” (Astronomy Picture of the Day). As the site explains, “Each day a different image or photograph of our fascinating universe is featured, along with a brief explanation written by a professional astronomer.” Although the commentary will not give God the glory for what is pictured, and though the explanations are not always consistent with Scripture, it is nonetheless breathtaking to see the handiwork of our amazing God in this way.</p>
<p>You may enjoy checking out the site, and may likewise find it an occasion for worship:</p>
<p><a href="http://apod.nasa.gov/apod/">http://apod.nasa.gov/apod/</a></p>
<p>To the praise of his glory!</p>
<p>–Pastor Greg</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/23/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Different Kind of Family Plan&#8230;</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/15/a-different-kind-of-family-plan/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/15/a-different-kind-of-family-plan/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 04:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Smith]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=966</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[Pornography: Not something we like to discuss, I know.  But this is a incredibly pervasive sin, and not talking about it, just allows the sin to remain hidden.  So many of us struggle with this, and yet, most of us have no intention of talking with anyone about it.  However, as Elihu says in Job [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pornography: Not something we like to discuss, I know.  But this is a incredibly pervasive sin, and not talking about it, just allows the sin to remain hidden.  So many of us struggle with this, and yet, most of us have no intention of talking with anyone about it.  However, as Elihu says in Job 34:21, God knows:</p>
<p>“For his eyes are on the ways of a man, and he sees all his steps.&#8221; Job 34:21</p>
<p>God sees it all, and nothing is hidden from Him.  Here&#8217;s an article written by Tim Challies that outlines a specific plan for dealing with the reality of instant internet access within the context of the Christian family.  It&#8217;s a very helpful, instructive and detailed overview of ways to protect your children (and yourselves) from the potential pitfalls of the digital content, specifically porn, now available whist retaining the immense usefulness that the digital medium affords.  This is a good read regardless of how many are currently in your family, 1 to 21 if you will.</p>
<div>
<p>Here&#8217;s the article:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.challies.com/articles/the-porn-free-family-plan#keep-reading">The Porn-Free Family Plan</a></p>
<p>~Geoff</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/15/a-different-kind-of-family-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Just another Sunday?</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/14/just-another-sunday/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/14/just-another-sunday/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 19:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Dave]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=958</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[Monday through Friday we have a routine and a plan. Make lunches. Lay out the kid’s clothes. Leave the house by 7:00 a.m. to beat the traffic. Check our calendar for appointments and deadlines. And so on. We know what it takes, and we’re committed to getting it done. Often, however, our approach to Sunday [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Monday through Friday we have a routine and a plan. Make lunches. Lay out the kid’s clothes. Leave the house by 7:00 a.m. to beat the traffic. Check our calendar for appointments and deadlines. And so on. We know what it takes, and we’re committed to getting it done. Often, however, our approach to Sunday morning does not receive the same attention. If we’re honest, it’s not a priority.</p>
<p>For the believer, gathering together with the body of Christ, to worship our Lord, to hear from the Scriptures, to serve and be served, this should be the highlight of our week. If we have decided to follow Christ, we have already declared that He is our highest goal, our prize of greatest value. Yet, our actions often betray our true allegiance as bosses, clients, appointments, kids activities, get our best planning and preparation.</p>
<p>Preparing for Sunday worship is more than just a matter of punctuality; it is a matter of the heart. Equally, if not more important, are our expectations. Are we passive observers or active participants?</p>
<p>Jordan Kauflin, recently posted a blog on <i>Desiring God</i> called “<a title="How Do You Prepare for Sunday?" href="http://www.desiringgod.org/blog/posts/how-do-you-prepare-for-sunday">How Do You Prepare for Sunday?</a>” In it, Kauflin talks about common mistakes we make in preparation for Sunday morning, and he gives some corrective suggestions. I would encourage you to click on the link, read the post, and evaluation your own Sunday preparation.</p>
<p>&#8211;Pastor Dave</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/14/just-another-sunday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Gospel is not&#8230;</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/04/the-gospel-is-not/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/04/the-gospel-is-not/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 19:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Steve]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=954</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[D. A. Carson comments on a very important issue that we must address in the 21st century church.  It is all too easy to redefine the gospel in terms that address gospel effects but are not the gospel.  The gospel of Jesus Christ results in transformed lives.  That transformation, in whatever form it takes, is [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>D. A. Carson comments on a very important issue that we must address in the 21st century church.  It is all too easy to redefine the gospel in terms that address gospel effects but are not the gospel.  The gospel of Jesus Christ results in transformed lives.  That transformation, in whatever form it takes, is the direct result of the transforming power of the gospel but those effects are not the gospel.  When we exchange the effects for the real thing we undermine the very gospel we proclaim to uphold.    This pattern has repeated itself time and again in the history of the church and it is a pattern we must be vigilant to avoid. Carson remarks,</p>
<blockquote><p>“By contrast, the first two greatest commands—to love God with heart and soul and mind and strength, and our neighbor as ourselves—do not constitute the gospel, or any part of it. We may well argue that when the gospel is faithfully declared and rightly received, it will result in human beings more closely aligned to these two commands. But they are not the gospel. Similarly, the gospel is not receiving Christ or believing in him, or being converted, or joining a church; it is not the practice of discipleship. Once again, the gospel faithfully declared and rightly received will result in people receiving Christ, believing in Christ, being converted, and joining a local church; but such steps are not the gospel.</p>
<p>The Bible can exhort those who trust the living God to be concerned with issues of social justice (Isa 2; Amos); it can tell new covenant believers to do good to all human beings, especially to those of the household of faith (Gal 6); it exhorts us to remember the poor and to ask, not “Who is my neighbor?” but “Whom am I serving as neighbor?” We may even argue that some such list of moral commitments is a necessary consequence of the gospel. But it is not the gospel. We may preach through the list, reminding people that the Bible is concerned to tell us not only what to believe but how to live. But we may not preach through that list and claim it encapsulates the gospel&#8230;</p>
<p>Failure to distinguish between the gospel and all the effects of the gospel tends, on the long haul, is to replace the good news as to what God has done with a moralism that is finally without the power and the glory of Christ crucified, resurrected, ascended, and reigning,&#8221;</p>
<p>- Pastor Steve</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/04/04/the-gospel-is-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Reminder About Marriage</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/26/a-reminder-about-marriage/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/26/a-reminder-about-marriage/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 19:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sguc]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=949</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[The issue of marriage is constantly in the news. Attempts to redefine it confront us daily, often in the form of news reports, political maneuverings, pontification from “experts,&#8221; and human interest stories. It is so crucial that we remind ourselves what God himself has to say about marriage, and why it matters. For this we [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The issue of marriage is constantly in the news. Attempts to redefine it confront us daily, often in the form of news reports, political maneuverings, pontification from “experts,&#8221; and human interest stories. It is so crucial that we remind ourselves what God himself has to say about marriage, and why it matters. For this we must turn to his Word, the Bible.</p>
<p>The Scriptures are so clear: marriage is ordained by God; it is to be between one man and one woman for life; and physical intimacy is to be limited to this relationship. But the Bible goes even further, revealing that marriage is also a representation of the gospel: husbands are to love their wives as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her; wives are to submit to their husbands as the church submits to Christ.</p>
<p>There is great confusion about marriage all around us, but the teaching of God’s Word has not changed, become dated or irrelevant. May we boldly affirm–and model–the beauty of God’s gracious design in this most fundamental of divinely-ordained institutions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Pastor Greg</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/26/a-reminder-about-marriage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dis Ciple Ship</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/19/dis-ciple-ship/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/19/dis-ciple-ship/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 22:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Smith]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=942</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[The word discipleship is to Christianity what the phrase &#8220;based on a true story&#8221; is to Hollywood.  It could mean almost anything&#8230;  Or at least that what it seems.  This word gets bandied about quite a bit, but what do we mean when we use it? Hard question to answer, because in reality, discipleship covers [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The word discipleship is to Christianity what the phrase &#8220;based on a true story&#8221; is to Hollywood.  It could mean almost anything&#8230;  Or at least that what it seems.  This word gets bandied about quite a bit, but what do we mean when we use it? Hard question to answer, because in reality, discipleship covers a lot of legitimate ground in the Christian life. So maybe it would be helpful to define it within a specific context, like say, Student Ministries Small Groups. When we say that through these Small Groups, we hope, by the grace of God, to disciple young people, what do we mean?</p>
<p>Well, I found myself nodding right along with a man named Randy Pope, who was interviewed by the Gospel Coalition, about the intramural church discipleship program that he has been using to great effect with his flock.  It&#8217;s drawn directly from the template that Christ himself used, and that we see in Scripture.  It happens to be pretty much exactly what we are trying to accomplish in Student Ministries, and to a larger degree in the entire church.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re not in a group like this, or being discipled by someone, and if you&#8217;re a mature (spiritually) believer, and you&#8217;re not pouring your life into someone(s), would you think and pray about how you might actively pursue becoming part of the discipleship happening here at SGCC?</p>
<p>Here is the interview with Randy Pope from The Gospel Coalition:</p>
<p>Note: You may need ear buds, or external speaker(s) to hear the audio, it&#8217;s pretty quiet.</p>
<p>[vimeo <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65324877" height="281" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/65324877">Deep Before Wide: A Vision for Returning Discipleship to the Church</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/gospelcoalition">The Gospel Coalition</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>~Geoff</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/19/dis-ciple-ship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Be ye funny, and do not sin&#8230;</title>
        <link>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/11/be-ye-funny-and-do-not-sin/</link>
        <comments>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/11/be-ye-funny-and-do-not-sin/#comments</comments>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 22:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Dave]]></dc:creator>
                <category><![CDATA[Sanctification]]></category>

        <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sgucblog.com/?p=935</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[Laughter is great. It is a human privilege. Animals may make us laugh. They do funny things on occasion (give your dog a spoonful of peanut butter if you don’t believe me). But animals are not intending to be funny. They don’t tell jokes. You won’t see a monkey at the zoo doing stand up, [&#8230;]]]></description>
                <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Screen-Shot-2014-03-11-at-9.18.03-AM.png"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-937" alt="Screen Shot 2014-03-11 at 9.18.03 AM" src="http://www.sgucblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Screen-Shot-2014-03-11-at-9.18.03-AM.png" width="151" height="163" /></a>Laughter is great. It is a human privilege. Animals may make us laugh. They do funny things on occasion (give your dog a spoonful of peanut butter if you don’t believe me). But animals are not intending to be funny. They don’t tell jokes. You won’t see a monkey at the zoo doing stand up, or a pig make a pun. Laughter is a gift from God, somehow tied to being made in his image.</p>
<p>Laughing with friends and family can be one of the greatest joys in life. I confess that I’m one of those who love a good joke, but can never remember them. Being a good joke-teller, like a good storyteller, is a gift. It can be developed, practiced, and caught by hanging around funny people, but by and large I believe you’re either born with it or you’re not.</p>
<p>Yet, like every good gift, when torn away from its God-centered, God-glorifying intention, it becomes another way to worship and serve the creature rather than the Creator. In other words, humor, like the rest of this fallen world in which we live is bent toward sin. Just think of how difficult it is to find a comedy from your local RedBox that does not contain a heavy dose of objectionable material.</p>
<p>Sadly, we often use humor like spiritual Novocain. The phrase, “It’s so funny,” will numb us to the reality that the content we are taking in is damaging to our soul, corrupting our view of God and His world, and stealing hours away from activity that might actually make a difference for eternity. If we are so bold to call into question the media discretion of a brother or sister in Christ, we are often met with the retort, “Well, what about the shows that you watch?,” or “You’re just being legalistic,” or the all excusing, “But it’s so funny.”</p>
<p>I don’t think this issue is new or peculiar to American Christians. In his book <i>The Screwtape Letters</i>, C. S. Lewis describes this same tendency in 1940s England. Here is a brief excerpt…</p>
<p><i>The real use of Jokes or Humour is in quite a different direction, and it is specially promising among the English, who take their “sense of humour” so seriously that a deficiency in this sense is almost the only deficiency at which they feel shame. Humour is for them the all-consoling and (mark this) the all-excusing, grace of life. Hence it is invaluable as a means of destroying shame. If a man simply lets others pay for him, he is “mean”; if he boasts of it in a jocular manner and twits his fellows with having been scored off, he is no longer “mean” but a comical fellow. Mere cowardice is shameful—unless the cruel man can represent it as a practical joke. A thousand bawdy, or even blasphemous, jokes do not help towards a man’s damnation so much as his discovery that almost anything he wants can be done, not only without the disapproval but with the admiration of his fellows, if only it can get itself treated as a Joke. And this temptation can be almost entirely hidden from your patient by that English seriousness about Humour. Any suggestion that there might be too much of it can be represented to him as “Puritanical” or as betraying a “lack of humour.”</i></p>
<p><i></i>Humor and laughter are gifts from God. Let’s celebrate it. Let’s enjoy it. Let’s redeem it. Let’s show the world that they didn’t invent humor, or laughter, the Creator of the world did.</p>
<p>Be ye funny, and do not sin.</p>
<p>&#8211;Pastor Dave</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <wfw:commentRss>http://www.sgucblog.com/2014/03/11/be-ye-funny-and-do-not-sin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
        <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
